Evelyn T. Palmer and Leigh Hunt Palmer science collection
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Evelyn T. Palmer and Leigh Hunt Palmer science collection
1971 - 2003
F-182
Q105669181
12.5 cm of textual records 17 sound recordings
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION Includes 11 audio reels and 11 audio cassettes; some of the cassettes are copies of the original reel-to-reel tapes.
Palmer, Evelyn T.
Evelyn T. and Leigh Hunt Palmer were active members of the Simon Fraser academic community from 1966 until their retirement in 2001. Leigh served as an associate professor of physics while Evelyn was a laboratory instructor in chemistry.
Both Palmers were active in university affairs and in scientific and cultural groups. They sponsored a number of seminars and lectures at SFU including the Albert Einstein Memorial Lecture Series, which they initiated on the one hundredth anniversary of the birth of Albert Einstein.
For further details of the Palmers' careers and achievements, see the autobiographical sketch in the Appendix (available only in the Archives reading room).
published
Full
Revised
The title is based on the names of the collectors, who are also subjects of the collection.
Collection consists of biographical information on the Palmers including an article from SFU Comment magazine; a binder (refiled in folders) on the history of the Department of Chemistry prepared by Evelyn T. Palmer; a group of files about the Albert Einstein Memorial Lecture Series (files F-182-0-0-0-4 to F-182-0-0-0-25 ) as well as reel-to-reel tapes and cassette recordings of the lectures; and a binder (refiled in folders) on various Faculty of Science lecture series organized by the Palmers. Collection includes correspondence, programs, posters, publications and other documents.
The files were arranged by the archivist.
Palmer, Evelyn T.; Palmer, Leigh Hunt; Faculty of Science; Department of Chemistry; Sound recordings; Textual records; Science and technology
The records were donated to the Simon Fraser University Archives by Evelyn and Leigh Hunt Palmer in 2003.
No further accruals are expected.
Files are open with no restrictions. Access to sound recordings may be restrictions for preservation reasons due to the age and fragility of the storage media (audio reel-to-reel and cassette tapes). Archives will provide access through digitization of the originals; consult the reference archivist for more details.
Auto-biographical sketches of Evelyn and Leigh Hunt Palmer are available in the hard copy version of the finding aid maintained in the Archives Reading Room.
- Biographical information about the Palmers, 1976 - 2003; F-182-0-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  published
  Textual records
  Pending review
- Chemistry Department history, vol. 1, 1971 - 1993; F-182-0-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
- Chemistry Department history, vol. 2, 1971 - 1993; F-182-0-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
- Einstein lectures: Organization, publicity, correspondence, vol. 1, 1979 - 1983; F-182-0-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-9.
- Von Baeyer, Hans, A Birthday Present for Albert Einstein, 14 March 1979; F-182-0-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-10.
- Klamkin, Murray, Problem Solving Using Transformation Theory, 13 October 1979; F-182-0-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-11.
- Unruh, W.G., Black Holes in Outer Space, 8 November 1979; F-182-0-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-12.
  - W.G. Unruh: Black Holes in Outer Space, November 8, 1979; F-182-0-0-0-7-1 (Audio reel OBJ-933)
    Unruh, W.G.; Sound recordings
    Open
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/3.
- Bartlett, N., Noble Gases, 13 December 1979; F-182-0-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-13.
  - N. Bartlett: Noble Gases, December 13, 1979; F-182-0-0-0-8-1 (Audio reel OBJ-934)
    Bartlett, Neil; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/4.
- Will, Clifford, Experimental Verification of General Relativity, 10 January 1980; F-182-0-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-14.
  - Clifford Will: Experimental Verification of General Relativity, January 10, 1980; F-182-0-0-0-9-1 (Audio reel OBJ-935)
    Will, Clifford; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/5.
- Harvey, H.H., Acid Rain, 12 February 1980; F-182-0-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-15.
  - H.H. Harvey: Acid Rain, February 12, 1980; F-182-0-0-0-10-1 (Audio reel OBJ-936)
    Harvey, Harold; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/6.
- Graham, R.L., The Shortest Network Problem, 13 March 1980; F-182-0-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-16.
  - Ron Graham: The Shortest Network Problem, March 13, 1980; F-182-0-0-0-11-1 (Audio reel OBJ-937)
    Graham, Ron; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/7.
- Oyama, Vance, Mars: Prolog to Life?, 7 May 1980; F-182-0-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-17.
  - Vance Oyama: Mars: Prolog to Life?, May 7, 1980; F-182-0-0-0-12-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-944, Audio cassette OBJ-945)
    Oyama, Vance; Sound recordings
    Duration: 1
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/8.
- Malone, S., Seismicity Associated with the Eruptions of Mount St. Helens, 13 November 1980; F-182-0-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-18.
  - Steve Malone: Seismicity Associated with the Erruptions of Mount St. Helens, November 13, 1980; F-182-0-0-0-13-1 (Audio reel OBJ-938)
    Malone, Steve; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/9.
- Baldwin, V., Why are Children's Diseases Special?, 11 December 1980; F-182-0-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-19.
  - V. Baldwin: Why are Children's Diseases Special?, December 11, 1980; F-182-0-0-0-14-1 (Audio reel OBJ-939)
    Baldwin, Virginia; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/10.
- Hofstaedter, Douglas, Self-Reference, Intelligence, and Frame Breaking: Spinoffs from Themes in Godel, Escher, Bach, 12 February 1981; F-182-0-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-20.
  - Douglas Hofstaedter: Self-Reference, Intelligence, and Frame Breaking: Spinoffs from Themes in Godel, Escher, Bach, February 12, 1981; F-182-0-0-0-15-1 (Audio reel OBJ-940)
    Hofstaedter, Douglas; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/11.
- Hoyle, G., What Insects Can Learn--and How They Do It, 12 March 1981; F-182-0-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-21.
  - G. Hoyle: What Insects Can Learn -- and How They Do It, March 12, 1981; F-182-0-0-0-16-1 (Audio reel OBJ-941)
    Hoyle, Graham; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/12.
- Israel, Werner, Black Holes, 14 March 1981; F-182-0-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-22.
  - Werner Israel: Black Holes, May 14, 1981; F-182-0-0-0-17-1 (Audio reel OBJ-942)
    Israel, Werner; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/14.
- Heilbron, John, Physics, Philanthropy and The First Nobel Prizes, 9 April 1981; F-182-0-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-23.
  - John Heilbron: Physics, Philanthropy and the First Nobel Prizes, April 9, 1981; F-182-0-0-0-18-1 (Audio reel OBJ-943)
    Heilbron, John L.; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/13.
- Johnson, Torrence V., Encounter with a Ringed Planet: The Voyage Mission to Saturn, 23 September 1981; F-182-0-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-24.
- Calvin, Melvin, Petplants, 12 October 1982; F-182-0-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-25.
- Peebles, James, The Expanding Universe, 24 February 1982; F-182-0-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-26.
  - James Peebles: The Expanding Universe, February 24, 1982; F-182-0-0-0-21-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-946, Audio cassette OBJ-947)
    Peebles, James; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/17.
- Ramsay, Donald A., ETS -- Extraterrestrial Spectroscopy, 24 March 1983; F-182-0-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-27.
  - Donald A. Ramsay: ETS - Extraterrestrial Spectroscopy, March 24, 1983; F-182-0-0-0-22-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-948)
    Ramsay, Donald A.; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/18.
- Taunton, Jack, Running Injuries, 13 October 1983; F-182-0-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-28.
  - Jack Taunton: Running Injuries, October 13, 1983; F-182-0-0-0-23-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-949, Audio cassette OBJ-950, Audio cassette OBJ-951)
    Taunton, Jack; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/19.
- Babai, Laszlo, Do Lawyers Need Large Prime Numbers....?, 26 January 1984; F-182-0-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-29.
  - Laszlo Babai: Do Lawyers Need Large Prime Numbers?, January 26, 1984; F-182-0-0-0-24-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-952)
    Babai, Laszlo; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/20.
- Cowley, Anne, It's a Brand New Black Hole, 15 March 1984; F-182-0-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
  Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-24-2-0-0-30.
  - Anne Cowley: It's a Brand New Black Hole, March 15, 1984; F-182-0-0-0-25-1 (Audio cassette OBJ-953, Audio cassette OBJ-954)
    Cowley, Anne; Sound recordings
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 100/11/9/21.
- Faculty of Science lecture series, 1975 - 1987; F-182-0-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 182-1)
- Lambda: SFU Science Undergraduate Journal, 1974 - 1975; F-182-0-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 182-1)